iodine.com 2017-11-10

# Privacy Policy - Iodine.com

## We lock personally identifying information to protect you

### We unlock real-life experience data for medical research

#### This policy is effective as of September 5, 2015

##### When you share information about your real-life health experiences on Iodine, you help others understand their options. You also help us in our mission to build a powerful resource for medical research that we hope can help make health information and products safer and more effective for everyone, including you.

Your Shared Data may be shared with our Partners.

Private Data []

On Iodine, we’ll sometimes ask you for information that identifies you personally (such as your name or email address). We mark this Private Data with a lock symbol []. We only share Private Data with your permission, or in some standard ways that we tell you about very clearly in our Privacy Policy.

  * For example
  * Your name, your email address

Shared Data []

Shared Data is any information you provide on Iodine that’s not Private Data. This includes any demographic info or real-life experience that you choose to submit (such as your age, gender, medications, conditions, or drug ratings and reviews). If you don’t see a lock symbol [] next to the field you’re completing, the information you enter is Shared Data. It’s shared publicly on Iodine to help other users. Also, unless you opt out, we share it with trusted Iodine partners, such as medical researchers and collaborators.

  * For example
  * Female, 61
  * Takes **lisinopril** for high **blood pressure.**
  * ‘I started having a dry cough after taking this medication, and I’m thinking about switching.’

Statistical Data

We share statistics about our users publicly on Iodine and with trusted Iodine partners, such as medical researchers and collaborators.

  * For example
  * ‘53% of women aged 35-54 thought this medication was worth it.’

###### Control your privacy

  *  **Don’t publicly share information** that can be used to identify or contact you. For example, don’t write your name in a review about a medication.
  *  **Share as much or as little about your experiences as you want.** For example, you can post comments about a medication without sharing your age, gender, or medical conditions.
  *  **Opt out of sharing Shared Data** with trusted Iodine partners.
  *  **Look next to the** [] any time you submit information to see your opt-out status. 

###### Privacy policy

###### What information we collect and how we use it  
To help you understand and improve your health

###### About this privacy policy

We know that when you use Iodine, you’re trusting us with your information. This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use, and share your information. We want it to be easy for anyone (not just lawyers) to understand. Send feedback to [privacy@iodine.com](mailto:privacy@iodine.com).

Unless we define a term in this Privacy Policy, all capitalized words we use here have the same meanings as in our Terms of Use.

This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use, and share your information. We’ve tried to make it easy to understand.

###### Changes

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time. We may solicit user feedback about changes but are under no obligation to use it. We’ll notify you of any changes in one or more of the following ways at least 30 days before changes are implemented:

  * By email
  * On the Iodine website

Our Privacy Policy might change. We’ll let you know at least 30 days before that happens.

###### Information we collect

###### Information you give us

Information you give us when you use Iodine might include:

  * Personally identifying information, such as your name or email address
  * Demographic information, such as age and gender
  * Health information, such as medications and conditions
  * Other real-life experience information, such as comments about your health or medications or responses to our surveys

For example, if you create an Iodine Account, we’ll collect certain information that can be used to identify you, such as your name, email address and phone number. If you create an Iodine Account using your login credentials from one of your SNS Accounts, we’ll be able to access and collect your name and email address and other personally identifying information that your privacy settings on the SNS Account permit us to access.

If you provide it to us, we may also collect other information that is not considered personally identifying information because it cannot be used by itself to identify you, such as your gender, age or date of birth.

We collect and store the information you choose to submit on Iodine. Certain information is required to create an Iodine Account.

###### Information we collect automatically

Like most websites and apps, we automatically collect certain information about how visitors use our services. We do this with automated data collection tools such as [server logs](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Server_log), [analytics](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_analytics), [cookies](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie), and [web beacons](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_beacon).

Through the Site: For example, when you use the Site, our server logs store your [IP address](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_address), browser type, operating system, and the pages you visited on Iodine. Here’s another example: we put a cookie (a marker) on your browser so our website knows that you already completed a survey about a drug and doesn’t ask you to do it again. Cookies are stored on your hard drive. On the other hand, web beacons are usually embedded on webpages or in e-mails. Like server logs, web beacons can also tell us what pages you visited on the Site.

Through the Iodine Apps: When you use an Iodine App, we collect certain information that your mobile device sends when you use the Iodine App, like a device identifier, user settings and the operating system of your device, as well as information about your use of Iodine.

Location Information: We may also collect and store information about your location by converting your IP address into a rough geo-location or by accessing your mobile device’s GPS coordinates or coarse location if you enable location services on your device. If you do not want us to collect location information, you may disable that feature on your mobile device.

Some third-party service providers that we engage (including third-party analytics service providers) may also use their own automated data collection tools, including placing their own cookies on your hard drive. Note that this Privacy Policy does not apply to these third parties.

Also, we automatically collect standard information about how visitors use our services.

###### How we use information

We use the information we collect in order to:

  * Understand how people use our services
  * Make our Site and the Iodine more secure
  * Provide you with our services
  * Communicate with you
  * Customize your experience
  * Conduct research
  * Improve and develop products and services

We use this information to provide and improve our services.

###### How we share information

###### Private Data

“Private Data” is any personally identifying information we ask you for or automatically collect. This is information that’s so specific that one piece of information alone (such as your full name or email address, or the location of your computer) can be used to identify or contact you.

If we ask you for personally identifying information, you’ll see the []. This lets you know that the information you are submitting is Private Data.

  * Examples of Private Data we may ask you for: Your name or email address
  * Example of Private Data we collect automatically: Your [IP address](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_address) (which can identify your computer’s location)

We won’t share Private Data with anyone unless it’s permitted in this Privacy Policy. If not, we’ll ask your permission first.

If you see the [], the information you’re submitting is Private Data.

We only share Private Data with your permission, or in some standard ways that we tell you about very clearly in this Privacy Policy

###### Shared Data

“Shared Data” is any information you provide that isn’t Private Data. If you don’t see the [], the information you’re submitting is Shared Data.

Shared Data may include:

  * Demographic information you give us, such as age and gender
  * Health information you give us, such as medications and conditions
  * Your User Submissions (as explained in our Terms of Use. User Submissions are anything that you share publicly on Iodine, such as survey responses and reviews about health experiences, medications, or side effects)

Your User Submissions are shared with everyone because you post them publicly on Iodine.

We also share Shared Data with trusted third parties (including academic and commercial organizations, collaborators, and customers) for specific purposes, such as medical research. We refer to these trusted third parties as our “Partners.” You can opt out of sharing your Shared Data with our Partners, but only if you submit that Shared Data via the Site. You cannot opt-out of sharing your Shared Data with our Partners if you submit that Shared Data via an Iodine App.

Even if you have an Iodine Account, your opt-out is not associated with a particular login or user account. Therefore, if you opt out via the Site, we’ll track your opt-out choice by placing a cookie on your device that will tell us that you have opted out. If you delete the Iodine cookie from your device, please remember that you’ll have to opt out again on Iodine to opt out of sharing any new Shared Data that you submit after deleting the cookie. You can hover over the [] on the Site to check your opt-out status.

While using Iodine, you might share multiple pieces of real-life information that could identify you, if combined. It’s also possible to include personally identifying information in free-text fields this information will still be treated as Shared Data, so be careful. It’s your choice whether to provide Shared Data and what to include when you post publicly.

If you don’t see the [], the information you’re submitting is Shared Data.

Shared Data includes anything you post publicly on Iodine.

We share Shared Data with trusted Iodine partners unless you opt out.

###### Statistical Data

“Statistical Data” is information we combine and analyze on an aggregated basis. It doesn’t identify individuals.

  * Example: “34% of patients ages 30-39 experienced nausea from this medication.”

We may also share it publicly on Iodine and with our Partners for industry research and analysis, demographic profiling, and other similar purposes.

We share general statistical information about users publicly on Iodine and with our Partners.

###### Our service providers

We may share information with third party companies and individuals that provide services to us, such as database management and web analytics.

These third-party services providers may have access to your Private Data, but only for the purpose of performing services on our behalf, and they are expressly obligated not to disclose or use your Private Data for any other purpose.

We might share information with people and companies that provide services to us—for example, companies that help us manage and analyze data.

###### For our protection and the protection of others

We may share information (including Private Data) with government, law enforcement, or private parties if we believe it’s necessary or appropriate:

  * To enforce our Terms of Use, including investigating potential violations
  * To detect and prevent activity that we consider illegal, fraudulent or unethical
  * To protect the property, rights and safety of us, our users, or the public in general
  * To respond to claims, law enforcement requests and subpoenas (we’ll notify you about this if we’re allowed to)

We might share information if we think it’s required by law or to protect Iodine and our users—for example, to investigate if someone tries to hack our site or any Iodine app.

###### In the event of a business trans

If Iodine, Inc. has a business merger, acquisition, reorganization, sale of assets, or bankruptcy, all of our assets will be sold or transferred, including any information you’ve shared with us.

Your information may be transferred if Iodine is transferred to a new owner.

###### Your privacy choices

You can:

  * Choose what information you give us.
  * Choose what information you share publicly on Iodine.
  * Choose whether to share your individual, real-life experiences (which may be shared publicly on Iodine or with trusted Partners).
  * Opt out of sharing your Shared Data with our Partners.

You choose what to submit and share on Iodine. You can opt out of sharing your Shared Data with our Partners.

###### The security of your information

We take reasonable measures to protect the information that we collect from or about you (including your Private Data) from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure.

For example, our employees may not access Private Data unless they need it to do a specific job, and they’re subject to strict confidentiality rules.

We also use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption on Iodine. Please be aware, however, that no method of transmitting information over the Internet or storing information is completely secure, so we can’t guarantee the absolute security of any information.

Data security is a priority for us. We use SSL encryption.

###### Modifying your information

Please note that in general, once submitted, your User Content can’t be deleted. In particular, your User Submissions can’t be deleted and will continue to appear on Iodine.

If you have an Iodine Account, you may be able to modify or remove certain User Content that you submitted via your Iodine Account.

If you don’t have an Iodine Account, and you want to remove some of your User Content from Iodine, please email us at [privacy@iodine.com](mailto:privacy@iodine.com). We may request further information from you to verify that you are the user who submitted the User Content in question. We’ll consider your request on an individual basis, and we may (but are not obligated to) take steps to delete your User Content. Even you delete or we take steps at your request to delete specific User Content, some of your User Content may remain in archived/backup copies for our records or as otherwise required by law, and as we indicated above, your User Content will continue to exist on the Services. We’re not responsible or liable for the removal or deletion of (or the failure to remove or delete) any of your User Content.

In general, we can’t delete User Content. If you have an Iodine Account, you may be able to modify some User Content. We’ll consider removal requests, but we’re not obligated to remove User Content.

You can choose to unsubscribe from any email from Iodine via the link provided in the email.

You can opt-out of all communications from Iodine by sending an e-mail to [privacy@iodine.com](mailto:privacy@iodine.com) or by calling (415) 935-3463.

###### Links to other sites

Our services may contain links to other websites and services. Any information that you provide on or to a third-party website or service is provided directly to the owner of the website or service and is subject to that party’s privacy policy, not ours. To protect your information, we recommend that you carefully review the privacy policies of other websites and services that you access.

Be careful when visiting third-party websites, even if you access them through Iodine. Our Privacy Policy doesn’t apply to third-party websites.

###### International transfer

Your information (including your Private Data) may be transferred to, and maintained on, computers located outside of your jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. If you’re located outside the United States and use Iodine, we may transfer your information to the United States and process it there.

If you use Iodine outside of the United States, any information you give us will be transferred to the United States.

###### Child privacy

Our services are not intended or designed for children under 13, and we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under 13. If you find out that your child has provided us with personal information without your consent, contact us at [privacy@iodine.com](mailto:privacy@iodine.com). If we find out that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information, we’ll take steps to delete that information from our files as soon as possible.

We’re committed to protecting the privacy of children and complying with privacy laws.

###### Questions?

Contact us at [privacy@iodine.com](mailto:privacy@iodine.com) if you have any questions about our Privacy Policy.

###### Opt-out

###### Opt out of sharing certain information with medical research partners

Sharing your real-life experiences on Iodine helps build a powerful resource for medical research. It can make health products safer and more effective for everyone, including you. That’s why we share our users’ Shared Data with trusted Partners (including academic and commercial research organizations) for specific purposes, such as medical research.

Here’s an example of the kind of Shared Data we might share with our Partners:

>  **Female, 61.** Takes **lisinopril** for **high blood pressure.** ‘I started having a dry cough after taking this medication, and I’m thinking about switching.’ (We’ll never share personally-identifying information, like your name or email address, with Partners without your permission.)

You can choose to opt out of sharing certain Shared Data with our Partners. This only applies to the Shared Data that you submit via the Site. It does not apply to Shared Data you submit via an Iodine App. If you choose to opt out via the Site, we’ll put a cookie (marker) on your browser so that we know not to share any future Shared Data you submit via the Site with our Partners.

Opt out of sharing your Shared Data to:

  * Stop sharing with our Partners. (You can still share on Iodine with other users.)
  * Stop sharing from now on. (Information you submitted before opting out may still be shared with our Partners.)
  * Stop sharing individual information only. (You can still be included in Statistical Data we share with our Partners, for example “75% of users thought Drug X was effective”.)

Remember: Since we track your opt-out with a cookie, if you delete your cookies you’ll need to opt out again via the Site. You can look next to the [] on the Site any time to check your opt-out status.

Your Shared Data may be shared with our Partners.

What is your question about?

Your question

Your email

We need your email to send you an answer.

Disclaimer: We don't provide medical advice. If you think you might have a medical emergency, call your doctor or 911 immediately.
